electricgeneratorsdirect.com 2019-01-13

# Privacy Policy @ Electric Generators Direct.com - Your Online Electric Generator Superstore

[](http://www.bbb.org/chicago/business-reviews/industrial-equipment-and-supplies/power-equipment-direct-in-bolingbrook-il-57001088) **Privacy Policy - Power Equipment Direct, Inc.**

**1) General**   
Power Equipment Direct, Inc. respects the privacy of every individual who visits our websites or responds to our guestbooks, contests, or interactive advertisements. This Privacy statement outlines the information Power Equipment Direct will collect and how we will use that information. This Statement will inform you what to do if you do not want your personal information to be shared or divulged when you visit a Power Equipment Direct website or respond to our advertising. Power Equipment Direct reserves the right to change this policy at any time by posting a new privacy policy at this location, and your continued use of our website indicates your acceptance of such changed terms. 

**2) Personally- Identifiable Information**   
Power Equipment Direct will not collect any personally-identifiable information about you (that is your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it voluntarily and knowingly. 

If you do not want your personally - identifiable information collected do not submit it to us. If you do submit personally identifiable information, we will use it in the following ways, unless stated otherwise: 

  * We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customizing future shopping suggestions, improving our store, and fulfilling your order.
  * We will and you authorize us to share your personal information with third parties to facilitate servicing your order. This includes, but is not limited to, sharing with our technology vendors (like our CRM provider), payment processors, fulfillment vendors (our suppliers), and shipping carriers.
  * We may share your personal information with the manufacturer of the product you purchase in order to register your product for warranty. If you request one or more installer to contact you during checkout, we will share your personal information with installers for that purpose.
  * We may store and process that information to better understand your needs and how we can improve our product offerings and services.
  * We will not give or sell your individual information to non-related companies for use in marketing or solicitations.
  * We may provide your information to related companies such as Build.com, Living Direct, Inc. or other companies in common ownership with Ferguson Enterprises, Inc.
  * Will maintain the confidentiality of your personal information, and it will only be used to support your relationship with Power Equipment Direct, its Web sites and to further develop your relationship with Power Equipment Direct and its related companies.

Unfortunately, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy statement. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. 

We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose us to legal liability. Therefore, although we will protect your privacy as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that all your personally identifiable information or private communications will remain private. 

**3) Children (under thirteen)**   
Power Equipment Direct, Inc. has no intention of collecting any personally identifiable information (that is your name, address, telephone number, or email address) from individuals under thirteen years of age through this website. The Power Equipment Direct websites that do collect information from Children do so in accordance with the privacy policies located at such websites. 

Please review such privacy policies when entering those sites. If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information a parent or guardian should contact us at the e-mail address listed at the bottom of this statement if they want this information to be deleted from the records. We will use all reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our existing files. 

**4) Non- Personally - Identifiable Information Collected Automatically**   
In some cases, we may collect information about you that is not personally-identifiable. Examples of this type of information include the Internet browser you a using, the type of operating system, and the domain name of the website which linked you to our site. When you view one of our websites, we may store information from time to time on your computer. These \"Cookies\" allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences. With most Internet Browsers you can block, receive a warning or erase all \"Cookies\" from your hard drive.

Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. We also collect an IP address from all visitors to our website. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our website, analyze trends, track users' movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are also not linked to personally identifiable information.   
We use third party services to improve customers' on-site and off-site experiences. This means aggregating and analyzing data that we obtain while you interact with our company. As examples, we use third party services to capture information about browsing behavior so that we can discover ways to improve our websites. We also use third party services to personalize product recommendations. 

**5) Opting Out of Receiving Communications from Us**   
Electric Generators Direct, Inc. may send you communications regarding its services, its websites or otherwise. Electric Generators Direct provides you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such communications by indicating your desire to opt-out. If you would like to opt out of receiving communications from us please email us at [service@electricgeneratorsdirect.com](mailto:service@electricgeneratorsdirect.com). 

**6) Correcting or Updating Information**   
At any time, you can view, update and/or remove your account information. Upon your request, we will also remove any other personally identifying information we may retain from our databases. To make any such changes or requests, please email us at [service@electricgeneratorsdirect.com](mailto:service@electricgeneratorsdirect.com). Additional residual information may remain in our archives and records, but this information will not be used for any commercial purpose. We reserve the right to maintain information on users who have violated our Terms of Use or who have had their access to our website blocked. 

**7) Security:**   
All information provided to Power Equipment Direct is transmitted using GeoTrust certified encryption. GeoTrust is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also protect your information by placing it on a secure portion of our website that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of Power Equipment Direct. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information. 

**8) Other Web Sites:**   
Power Equipment Direct, Inc. websites contains links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which Power Equipment Direct has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours. Also, you may have entered this website from an unrelated third party website. Likewise, Power Equipment Direct has no responsibility for such third party websites and you should review their privacy statements. 

**9) Interest-Based Advertising:**   
Data about your activities online is being collected on our Site for use in providing advertising tailored to your individual interests. You may choose whether or not to have your information collected for that purpose. This section of the Privacy Policy provides details and explains how to exercise that choice.   
We sometimes work with online advertising vendors to provide you with relevant and useful ads.  This may include ads served on other companies’ websites. These ads may also be based on your activities on our websites or on third party websites.  

To opt out of having your online behavior collected for advertising purposes, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**10) Your California Privacy Rights:**   
If you live in California and have an established business relationship with us, you can request a list of the personal information we have shared with third parties for their marketing purposes. We will also give you a list of the third parties that have received your information. You can make a request one time each year.

To exercise your rights, you can write to us at the address below. Mention in your letter that you are making a "California Shine the Light" inquiry.

Attn: Privacy Compliance

Power Equipment Direct, Inc.  
969 Veterans Parkway Suite C  
Bolingbrook, IL 60490

**11) Changes to this Privacy and Security Statement:**

**Effective Date:**  January 1, 2003  
**Last Revision Date:**  April 6, 2018  
From time to time we may change our privacy policies. We will notify you of any material changes to our Privacy Statement by posting an updated copy on our website. Please check our website periodically for updates.

**12) Contacting Power Equipment Direct:**   
If you have any questions about this Privacy statement, the practices of this website, or your dealings with this website, you can contact: 

Power Equipment Direct, Inc.   
969 Veterans Parkway Suite C   
Bolingbrook, IL 60490 

Thank you.
